Alright, the last thing you want to take a look at is context.
And when I'm talking about context, I'm talking about the actual space that you are going to speak in.
First of all, how big is your audience?
Are you going to be speaking to twenty people?
Are you going to be speaking to five hundred people?
The topic that you choose and the level of intimacy in which you present it, will vary dramatically, for twelve or twenty people versus five hundred people.
You also need to take a look at the time of day that you're giving your speech.
If you're doing the speech right before lunch, you might not want to do a speech about delicious food.
Because your audience might not be able to concentrate because they're so hungry that they want to go get some delicious food.
Or, you might not want to do something that might be boring to them because they're so hungry, they've got that internal noise going on and they're not listening to anything you say, because they are hungry.